<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford Computational Journalism Lab</title>
    <description>Computational methods in the pursuit of accountability journalism and data-driven storytelling.</description>
    <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://cjlab.stanford.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:36:43 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:36:43 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic, adaptable project organization</title>
        <description>AP DataKit is an open-source command-line tool designed to better structure and manage projects. 
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/09/01/basic-adaptable-project-organization/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/09/01/basic-adaptable-project-organization/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stanford Journalism alums launch immersive experience featuring Mandy Barker photography</title>
        <description>The virtual reality experience, Ripple — the unintended life of plastics in the sea, is now viewable at https://rippleplastic.com/. Featuring the photography of artist and conservationist Mandy Barker, the experience immerses viewers into a galaxy of garbage, to show how ubiquitous, insidious and long-lasting plastic can be in our world. 
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/08/01/stanford-jounalism-alums-launch-immersive-experience-featuring-mandy-barker-photography/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/08/01/stanford-jounalism-alums-launch-immersive-experience-featuring-mandy-barker-photography/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making news the &quot;Big Local&quot; way</title>
        <description>Investigative journalists collaborated with the Stanford Big Local News team to collect, clean and archive the data. This deposit was collected as part of the investigations that lead to articles published by Newsy, Reveal, and ProPublica into how police process rape cases.
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/07/01/making-news-the-big-local-way/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/07/01/making-news-the-big-local-way/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deceit gets smarter. Can truth keep up?</title>
        <description>Artificial intelligence is remaking the news. Those who control it are reshaping society.
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/07/01/deceit-gets-smarter-can-truth-keep-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/07/01/deceit-gets-smarter-can-truth-keep-up/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stanford grad trades STEM for storytelling</title>
        <description>Stanford scientist and graduating doctoral student Irena Fischer-Hwang made a new discovery during her studies at Stanford: a passion for data-driven news. She will be coming back to the Farm in the fall to pursue a second degree; this time, a master’s in communication.
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/06/13/stanford-grad-trades-stem-for-storytelling/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/06/13/stanford-grad-trades-stem-for-storytelling/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A commitment to her Native American roots leads Stanford's Aliyah Chavez to a journalism career</title>
        <description>After Stanford, Aliyah Chavez will pursue dual passions for reporting the news and drawing attention to the issues of indigenous communities as a journalist for Indian Country Today. She’ll work on a PBS program for Native American peoples created by Native American journalists.
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/06/12/a-commitment-to-her-native-American-roots-leads-stanfords-Aliyah-Chavez-to-a-journalism-career/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2019/06/12/a-commitment-to-her-native-American-roots-leads-stanfords-Aliyah-Chavez-to-a-journalism-career/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stanford scholars are helping journalists do investigative journalism through data</title>
        <description>A team of Stanford University scholars are launching a data-driven initiative to help journalists find stories at a lower cost, to support local newsrooms explore public interest issues and fight against misinformation.
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2018/10/15/stanford-scholars-are-helping-journalists-do-investigative-journalism-through-data/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2018/10/15/stanford-scholars-are-helping-journalists-do-investigative-journalism-through-data/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Local News harnesses investigative journalists’ expertise to empower local newsrooms</title>
        <description>Stanford’s Big Local News program is expanding with the addition of two investigative journalists — Pulitzer Prize winner Justin Mayo and data reporter Bethney Bonilla. Mayo and Bonilla join Eric Sagara, a senior data reporter with Reveal from The Center for Investigative Reporting, who is working with the Big Local News program for a year with support of the JSK Journalism Fellowships. The team of faculty, students and researchers is led by computational journalist and lecturer Cheryl Phillips.
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2018/09/01/big-local-news-harnesses-investigative-journalists-expertise-to-empower-local-news/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2018/09/01/big-local-news-harnesses-investigative-journalists-expertise-to-empower-local-news/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investigating Tech — The Making of &quot;The Facebook Dilemma&quot;</title>
        <description>How did Frontline investigate Facebook’s impacts on democracy across the globe? What is the story behind the story, including the challenges to covering a social media platform? Frontline Producers Anya Bourg and James Jacoby along with Washington Post Investigative Reporter Dana Priest discuss the processes and obstacles in examining the Silicon Valley giant.
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2017/11/08/investigating-tech-the-making-of-the-facebook-dilemma/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2017/11/08/investigating-tech-the-making-of-the-facebook-dilemma/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A conversation with Bob Woodward</title>
        <description>Bob Woodward — the best-selling author whose reporting has earned The Washington Post two Pulitzer Prizes, including for groundbreaking coverage of the Watergate scandal — discusses his reporting from Nixon to Trump and the challenges confronting the press, the presidency, and American democracy. The event was part of the 53rd Carlos Kelly McClatchy Symposium. 
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2017/11/08/a-conversation-with-bob-woodward/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cjlab.stanford.edu/2017/11/08/a-conversation-with-bob-woodward/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
